EVGENI VESKOV NIKOLOV

UX/UI/Web Designer

+359 88 888 23 98

www.eveskov.com

mww.linkedin.com/in/eveskov

Sofia, Bulgaria



SUMMARY

I am a UX/UI/Web Designer, with more than 7 years of experience in the field of web and mobile app development. I create digital products and services that are intuitive and accessible. I am currently working on an educational project (GCSEHistory.com) at a startup company 9Sharp.

EXPERIENCE

2014 - Ongoing Sofia, BG

UX/UI/Web Designer

9Sharp

9Sharp is a startup company where I worked on multiple projects with various responsibilities:

- · Competitive research;
- · Wireframing and prototyping;
- UX/UI design for web app and native iOS and Android apps, based on Human Interface Guidelines by Apple and Material Design Guidelines by Google;
- Conversational UI design for Amazon Alexa and Google Assistant apps;
- Building an entire web app layout with HTML and CSS, using Vue.js/Nuxt.js frameworks;
- Layouts for native apps with Swift and Kotlin;
- Responsive design for the web app;
- · Design of landing pages;
- Email templates UI design and building in Send Grid (HTML and CSS)
- Graphic design for 44 print books and converting them from HTML to PDF, EPUB, and Kindle;
- Graphic design of print materials (posters, flyers, etc.);
- Cooperation with the development team;
- After successfully shipped GCSEHistory.com, we gained 2500+ users for less than 3 months with great feedback.

2004 - 2013 Shumen, BG

Graphic Designer

Polyprint

Polyprint is a flexo printing company. I was responsible for:

- Design of flexible packaging for various products
- Prepress to the specifics of the flexo technology
- I worked with Bulgarian and foreign clients
- · Quality control of the printing process

CV | Evgeni Veskov Nikolov 1

2003-2006

2009-2012

Shumen, BG

Part-time Assistant

Konstantin Preslavski University of Shumen

- Responsible for "Graphic Design" and "Software Skills" modules
- Teaching Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop
- Leading "Graphic Design" seminars

01.2007 - 11.2010 Shumen, BG

Chairman of the Society of Shumen Artists

Member of "International biennial for contemporary art" Association and Society of Shumen Artists.

The organizer of National painting plain-air (2007 and 2009) and team member in the organization at "II International biennial for contemporary art - Shumen'06".

Participation in over 20 national and international group exhibitions and 3 self exhibitions.

EDUCATION

07.2002 - 10.2003

Masters degree in Plastic Arts
Konstantin Preslavsky University of Shumen

09.1998 - 07.2002

Bachelors degree in Fine Art

Konstantin Preslavsky University of Shumen

SKILLS

Design

User Experience (interaction design, wireframing, prototyping, competitive research, empathy for the user), User Interface Design, User-centered Design, Sketching, Graphic Design (posters, logos, packaging).

Programming/Technical

HTML, CSS/SASS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, JavaScript (basics), Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Eleventy (11ty), Email templates, MailChimp, SendGrid, XAML (basics), SWIFT (basics), Command line (basics), Git (basics), WordPress, HTML/CSS to PDF.

Tools

Pen & Paper, Sketch, Figma, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, CorelDraw, Mindomo, WebStorm, VS Code.

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Creativity, Responsibility, Organized, Time management, Logical thinking, Analytical skills, Multi-tasking, Adaptability, Stress management, Keen to learn.

LANGUAGES

Bulgarian, English, Russian

CV | Evgeni Veskov Nikolov 2